Hello, I am Subita Maiti,
I am an advisor
and product
tenor of ICICI Prudential Insurance Company, Contai Branch. Today I will discuss a pension plan called
Guaranteed Pension Plan called
GPP
Flexing. Anyone between the ages of 40 and 70
can take this plan. It can be
taken with a minimum of Rs. 12,000. But yes, of
course it depends on the age. It can be taken for a
PPT term of five years, seven years, 10 years. The
money can be
started after five years,
any time
between five and 15 years, seven years, seven years, 15 years, and
again after 10 years, any
time between 10 and 15 years. There is an opportunity for premium waiver here. Let's say
a person
takes this plan at the age of 65. He will pay two lakh rupees for five years, that
is, he will pay two lakh rupees till the age of 65, 66, 67, 68, 69
and will get pension from the age of 70.
He thought about that.  He took this plan at the age of 65, that
is, he gave two lakh taka. Unfortunately, before
he could give two lakh taka again at the age of 66,
his nominee, that is, his wife, died. He did
not have to pay the remaining premiums, that is, four premiums, that is, 8 lakh
taka, which the company will give him.
He will start getting pension after 61 months after five years.
He will get pension on top of that 10 lakh taka and the person he nominates will
get the lump sum money in his absence.
There are
two ways to get pension.
One, I gave two lakh taka for five years.
10 lakh taka. Then I will start getting pension.
I will get pension in my absence.
My nominee will get pension in my absence. The person I nominate will
get the lump sum money in his absence.
Two booster
payouts. This means that I have paid two lakh taka for
five years. 10 lakh taka. I
started getting a pension. I
took some lump sum money every five years to get my pension.
In this case, but the
amount of my pension will not decrease. The way I am
getting my pension is the same.  I will continue to receive the same amount of pension
if it is seen that
my
part of the money has run out when
I take my pension, that is, the amount of money that I have been taking for at least five years has run out,
then I will not get anything in the end
or the nominee will not get anything because I have taken lump sum
money every five years.
Also, there are some benefits in
this
plan, such as to take this plan,
medical is not required and income proof is not required.
Also,
if someone starts getting pension today,
he will
get the same amount of pension as he will get in the end, whereas in the
bank post office, but there is
no guarantee there, if it becomes zero there, there is
no fear
here, but he will continue to get the same amount of money.
All these facilities are here,
so those of you who want to get pension can definitely
take this plan. This is a very good
plan. Guaranteed
plan. Thank
you all so much for today.
Greetings.